therapistaid.com 2019-05-08

# Privacy Policy | Therapist Aid

Your privacy is critically important to us. At Therapist Aid, we have a few fundamental principles:

  * We are thoughtful about the personal information we ask you to provide and the personal information that we collect about you through the operation of our website.
  * We store personal information for only as long as we have a reason to keep it.
  * We aim to make it as simple as possible for you to control what information is stored, shared, and permanently deleted.
  * We help protect you from overreaching government demands for your personal information.
  * We aim for full transparency on how we gather, use, and share your personal information.

Below is our Privacy Policy, which incorporates and clarifies these principles.

## What This Policy Covers

This Privacy Policy applies to information that we collect about you when you use our website, located at https://www.therapistaid.com. Throughout this Privacy Policy we’ll refer to this as the “Website.”

Below we explain how we collect, use, and share information about you, along with the choices that you have with respect to that information.

## Information We Collect

We only collect information about you if we have a reason to do so–for example, to provide our Website, to communicate with you, or to make our Website better.

We collect information in two ways: if and when you provide information to us, and automatically through operating our Website.

### Information You Provide to Us

It’s probably no surprise that we collect information that you provide to us. The amount and type of information depends on the context and how we use the information. Here are some examples:

  * Basic Account Information: We ask for basic information from you in order to set up your account. For example, we require individuals who sign up for a Therapist Aid account to provide a name and email address–and that’s it.
  * Transaction and Billing Information: If you buy something from us–such as a subscription to a Therapist Aid plan–you will provide additional personal and payment information that is required to process the transaction and your payment, such as your name, credit card information, and contact information.
  * Communications With Us: You may also provide us information when you respond to surveys or communicate with our support staff.

### Information We Collect Automatically

We also collect some information automatically:

  * Log Information: Like most online service providers, we collect information that web browsers, mobile devices, and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, IP address, unique device identifiers, language preference, referring site, the date and time of access, operating system, and mobile network information. We collect log information when you use our Website–for example, when you update your account information.
  * Usage Information: We collect information about your usage of our Website. For example, we collect information about how many worksheets are downloaded, or which interactive therapy tools are most popular. We use this information to, for example, provide our Website to you, as well as get insights on how people use our Website, so we can make our Website better.
  * Location Information: We may determine the approximate location of your device from your IP address. We collect and use this information to, for example, calculate how many people visit our Website from certain geographic regions.
  * Information from Cookies & Other Technologies: A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Pixel tags (also called web beacons) are small blocks of code placed on websites and emails. Therapist Aid uses cookies and other technologies like pixel tags to help us identify and track visitors, usage, and access preferences for our Website, as well as track and understand email campaign effectiveness and to deliver targeted ads. For more information about our use of cookies and other technologies for tracking, including how you can control the use of cookies, please see our Cookie Policy.

## How And Why We Use Information

### Purposes for Using Information

We use information about you as mentioned above and for the purposes listed below:

  * To provide our Website–for example, to set up and maintain your account, or charge you for any of our paid services;
  * To further develop and improve our Website–for example by adding new features or content that we think our users will enjoy;
  * To monitor and analyze trends and better understand how users interact with our Website, which helps us improve our Website and make it easier to use;
  * To measure, gauge, and improve the effectiveness of our advertising, and better understand user retention and attrition–for example, we may analyze how many individuals purchased a plan after receiving a marketing message or the features used by those who continue to use our Website after a certain length of time;
  * To monitor and prevent any problems with our Website, protect the security of our Website, detect and prevent fraudulent transactions and other illegal activities, fight spam, and protect the rights and property of Therapist Aid and others, which may result in us declining a transaction or the use of our Website;
  * To communicate with you, for example through an email, about offers and promotions offered by Therapist Aid and others we think will be of interest to you, solicit your feedback, or keep you up to date on Therapist Aid and our products; and
  * To personalize your experience using our Website, provide content recommendations, target our marketing messages to groups of our users (for example, those who have a particular plan with us or have been our user for a certain length of time), and serve relevant advertisements.

### Legal Bases for Collecting and Using Information

A note here for those in the European Union about our legal grounds for processing information about you under EU data protection laws, which is that our use of your information is based on the grounds that:

  * The use is necessary in order to fulfill our commitments to you under our Terms of Service or other agreements with you or is necessary to administer your account–for example, in order to enable access to our Website on your device or charge you for a paid plan; or
  * The use is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation; or
  * The use is necessary in order to protect your vital interests or those of another person; or
  * We have a legitimate interest in using your information–for example, to provide and update our Website, to improve our Website so that we can offer you an even better user experience, to safeguard our Website, to communicate with you, to measure, gauge, and improve the effectiveness of our advertising, and better understand user retention and attrition, to monitor and prevent any problems with our Website, and to personalize your experience; or
  * You have given us your consent–for example before we place certain cookies on your device and access and analyze them later on, as described in our Cookie Policy.

## Sharing Information

### How We Share Information

We do not sell our users’ private personal information.

We share information about you in the limited circumstances spelled out below and with appropriate safeguards on your privacy:

  * Subsidiaries, Employees, and Independent Contractors: We may disclose information about you to our subsidiaries, our employees, and individuals who are our independent contractors that need to know the information in order to help us provide our Website or to process the information on our behalf. We require our subsidiaries, employees, and independent contractors to follow this Privacy Policy for personal information that we share with them.
  * Third Party Vendors: We may share information about you with third party vendors who need to know information about you in order to provide their services to us. This group includes vendors that help us provide our Website to you (like payment providers that process your credit and debit card information, fraud prevention services that allow us to analyze fraudulent payment transactions, postal and email delivery services that help us stay in touch with you, and email support services that help us communicate with you), and those that assist us with our marketing efforts (e.g. by providing tools for identifying a specific marketing target group or improving our marketing campaigns). Other vendors are listed in our more specific policies (e.g. our Cookie Policy).
  * Legal Requests: We may disclose information about you in response to a subpoena, court order, or other governmental request.
  * To Protect Rights, Property, and Others: We may disclose information about you when we believe in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Therapist Aid, third parties, or the public at large. For example, if we have a good faith belief that there is an imminent danger of death or serious physical injury, we may disclose information related to the emergency without delay.
  * Business Transfers: In connection with any merger, sale of company assets, or acquisition of all or a portion of our business by another company, or in the unlikely event that Therapist Aid goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would likely be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. If any of these events were to happen, this Privacy Policy would continue to apply to your information and the party receiving your information may continue to use your information, but only consistent with this Privacy Policy.
  * With Your Consent: We may share and disclose information with your consent or at your direction. For example, we may share your information with third parties with which you authorize us to do so.
  * Aggregated or De-Identified Information: We may share information that has been aggregated or reasonably de-identified, so that the information could not reasonably be used to identify you. For instance, we may publish aggregate statistics about the use of our Website and we may share a hashed version of your email address to facilitate customized ad campaigns on other platforms.
  * Published Support Requests: And if you send us a request (for example, via a support email or one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish that request in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users.

## How Long We Keep Information

We generally discard information about you when we no longer need the information for the purposes for which we collect and use it–which are described in the section above on How and Why We Use Information–and we are not legally required to continue to keep it.

For example, we keep the web server logs that record information about visitors to the Website, such as the visitor’s IP address, browser type, and operating system, for approximately 30 days. We retain the logs for this period of time in order to, among other things, analyze traffic to the Website and investigate issues if something goes wrong.

## Choices

You have several choices available when it comes to information about you:

  * Limit the Information that You Provide: If you have an account with us, you can choose not to provide the optional account information, and transaction and billing information. Please keep in mind that if you do not provide this information, certain features of our Website–for example, paid subscriptions–may not be accessible.
  * Opt-Out of Electronic Communications: You may opt out of receiving promotional messages from us. Just follow the instructions in those messages. If you opt out of promotional messages, we may still send you other messages, like those about your account and legal notices.
  * Set Your Browser to Reject Cookies: You can choose to set your browser to remove or reject browser cookies before using Therapist Aid, with the drawback that certain features of the Website may not function properly without the aid of cookies.
  * Close Your Account: While we’d be very sad to see you go, if you no longer want to use our Website, you can close your account (contact us for account closure; see How to Reach Us below). Please keep in mind that we may continue to retain your information after closing your account, as described in How Long We Keep Information above–for example, when that information is reasonably needed to comply with (or demonstrate our compliance with) legal obligations such as law enforcement requests, or reasonably needed for our legitimate business interests.

## Your Rights

If you are located in certain countries, including those that fall under the scope of the European General Data Protection Regulation (AKA the “GDPR”), data protection laws give you rights with respect to your personal data, subject to any exemptions provided by the law, including the rights to:

  * Request access to your personal data;
  * Request correction or deletion of your personal data;
  * Object to our use and processing of your personal data;
  * Request that we limit our use and processing of your personal data; and
  * Request portability of your personal data.

You can usually access, correct, or delete your personal data using your account settings, but if you aren’t able to do that, or you would like to contact us about one of the other rights, scroll down to How to Reach Us to, well, find out how to reach us.

EU individuals also have the right to make a complaint to a government supervisory authority.

## How to Reach us

If you have a question about this Privacy Policy, or you would like to contact us about any of the rights mentioned in the Your Rights section above, please email us at [contact@TherapistAid.com](mailto:contact@TherapistAid.com).

## Other Things You Should Know

### Ads and Analytics Services Provided by Others

Ads appearing on our Website may be delivered by advertising networks. These ad networks and analytics providers may set tracking technologies (like cookies) to collect information about your use of our Website and across other websites and online services. These technologies allow these third parties to recognize your device to compile information about you or others who use your device. This information allows us and other companies to, among other things, analyze and track usage, determine the popularity of certain content, and deliver advertisements that may be more targeted to your interests. Please note this Privacy Policy only covers the collection of information by Therapist Aid and does not cover the collection of information by any third party advertisers or analytics providers.

## Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Therapist Aid may change its Privacy Policy from time to time. Therapist Aid encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. If we make changes, we will notify you by revising the change log below, and, in some cases, we may provide additional notice (such as adding a statement to our homepage, or sending you a notification through email). Your further use of the Website after a change to our Privacy Policy will be subject to the updated policy.

## Change Log

  * May 25th, 2018 - Privacy policy added.
